## **SAMMY SAMKOUGH**

862-239-0100 | sammysamkough@gmail.com | Wayne, NJ 07470

https://sammy.pizza | https://github.com/ssamkough | https://linkedin.com/in/ssamkough

## LARAVEL WEB APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER; OWL SERVICES

### **SUMMARY:**

**Software Engineer with over five years of diverse experience** developing web applications and building APIs.

Developing single-page, multi-page and mobile applications using PHP and JavaScript / TypeScript.

Areas of Expertise: WEB APP DEVELOPMENT // OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING (OOP) // APIS

### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:**

- Languages PHP; HTML; CSS; JavaScript; TypeScript; Python; C#; Java; SQL
- Frameworks Laravel; Vue.js; Nuxt; React.js; Next.js; Selenium; Playwright; Django; Node.js; React Native
- Applications Git; MySQL; PostgreSQL; Wordpress; GraphQL; Storybook; AWS; Google Cloud; Vercel; Linux

### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# Bonny Systems, New York City, NY; Wayne, NJ

Oct 2023 - Present

Founding Engineer

- Achieving over 80% reduction in website load times by improving core web vitals which includes minimizing JavaScript usage, image optimization, and adherence to web standards.
- Partnering with design agencies to build and deploy modern websites using content management systems (CMS) like WordPress or advanced frameworks such as PHP / Laravel, Vue.js, and Nuxt.

# Canal, San Francisco, CA; New York City, NY

May 2021 - Jul 2023

Software Engineer

- Developed and refined the onboarding process to adapt to evolving user needs, utilizing React, Next.js, TypeScript, XState, Django, GraphQL and PostgreSQL which lead to an overall 40% increase in user satisfaction.
- Collaborated with a design / product team of five to create our own in-house design system that replaced the Shopify Polaris design system which led to an increase of development speed by over 60%.
- Enhanced web application usability across all departments by 60% through leading targeted accessibility training and guidelines for the development team.
- Led the standardization of UI component testing within the in-house design system, significantly reducing component-specific bugs by over 70% using Chromatic and Storybook.

### Popstar, Remote USA

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021

Software Engineer

- Developed a feature-rich iOS application using Swift and PostgreSQL, which offered an elegant vertical video experience, including social interactions such as sharing and commenting on videos.
- Integrated push notifications and leveraged Firebase cloud messaging to enhance user engagement and retention.

# Decusoft, Hybrid (Ramsey, NJ; Remote USA)

May 2019 - Oct 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

- Developed several top requested features such as table filtering and sorting using JavaScript / Knockout.js, C# and SQL.
- Optimized complex SQL queries which increased the load time performance of the main MySQL table by 50%.

#### **EDUCATION:**

Montclair State University, Montclair, NJ

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science 2019